Priyanka Saggu

About

Summary

Resourceful DevOps enthusiast with experience in networking and programming. As a summer trainee at Dgplug, have set up and managed multiple Linux servers. Wrote IaC files to automate the setting up of tightly-secured and SSH-hardened systems/servers. Worked closely under the guidance of mentors from leading upstream open-source projects.

Personal Info

- Email: priyankasaggu11929@gmail.com
- Website: priyankasaggu119.wordpress.com
- Gitlab-gnome: https://gitlab.gnome.org/priyankasaggu119
- Gitlab-salsa: https://salsa.debian.org/priyankasaggu119-guest
- Github: https://github.com/Priyankasaggu11929/

Experience

Community Learning & Contributions

Dgplug Summer Training

2018-Present

- Set up and managed multiple Linux distribution servers.
- Wrote Ansible scripts to automatically update system components and setup production environments.
- Set up a WriteFreely multi-user instance behind reverse-proxy.
- Set up multiple Docker containers for carrying out test deployments.
- Wrote Infrastructure as Code (IaC) to setup SSH-hardened servers.
- Contributed to lymworkbook a Vagrant lab environment in setting up a few basic level sys-admins problems.

Debian

2019

- Packaged 4 django/flask dependency python modules under Debian-Python-Modules-Team (DPMT).
- Packaged and updated 5+ ruby-gems for Debian-Diaspora project under Debian-Ruby-Team (DRT).
- Contributed to the Debian-gitlab project under Debian-javascript-team (DJT). Improved old node modules, packaged new ones and was constantly involved in testing of Debian-gitlab for then-stable version release.

Gnome - gtranslator

2019-Present

- Improved UI by revamping existing GTK dialog widgets into Gedit style framing.
- Entirely redesigned new GtK Dialogs in accordance with Gnome Human Interface Guidelines(HIG).
- Refactored and improved some part of major deprecated code.

Internships

• Learn IT, Girl (Certificate) Scholar mentee - 2019

• GeeksforGeeks, Noida (Certificate) Graphics designer intern - 2018

Education

- B.Tech in Computer Science & Engineering Deenbandhu Chhotu Ram University of Science & Technology, Murthal (Sonepat), Haryana 2015-2019
- AISSCE (12th-PCM) Govt. Model Senior Secondary School, Sector 35-D, Chandigarh (U.T.) 2014-2015
- AISSE (10th) S.B.P. D.A.V Centenary Public School, Fatehabad, Haryana 2012-2013

Conferences/Events

- · 2019 PyCon, India
- 2019 DebUtsav Delhi
- 2017 International Conference on Textile Advances-TAI India

Writings

Self

- A guide to a "safer" SSH!
- Containerisation using Docker!
- Let's get started with iptables!
- Automating WordPress Installation Through Ansible!
- Setting up WriteFreely multi-user instance in production!

Publications

- Introduction to Xamarin | A Software for Mobile App Development and App Creation
- Flutter | An Introduction to the Open Source SDK by Google

Skills/Keywords

- Linux: Debian family (Ubuntu, Debian Buster), Red Hat family (CentOS)
- Scripting: Bash and utils, Python
- Backend: Python (Django)
- Frontend: HTML, CSS, Javascript (JQuery, PhaserJS)
- Databases: MySQL, SQLite
- Web Application servers/proxies: Nginx, Apache2
- Version control systems: Git
- DevOps: Ansible, Docker, Server Management, Security
- Misc: Google Cloud Platform (GCP), OpenCV, Java-J2SE